Declan Chew

Sound Recordist (Production Sound)

Areas of Expertise

PSC-style productions

Commercial / Branded

Documentary

Narrative

Corporate

Post Production Sound

Music Production

Personal Audio Kit List

Zoom F8 Field Recorder
Sennheiser MKH 50 & 60
Shotgun Microphones
Sennheiser G3
Radio Mic Sets
Sanken Cos-11D and
Sennheiser MKE-2 Gold
Lavalier Microphones
IEM systems for Director,
Script, etc.
Tentacle Sync timecode units
Adam A7 Studio Monitors
Protools

Logic

Career Summary

Experienced in the field of sound and music since 2004
Based in London working in production sound since 2013

Have assisted Production Sound Mixers such as Ian Voigt, Jake Whitelee, Andy Hewitson, Cassandra Rutledge, and more

Pleasure having worked with Giggs, Dua Lipa, Elaine Page, David Essex, Alter Bridge, Ander Herrera, the Chuckle Brothers, Virat Kohli, and more

Projects with brands such as EE, Tesco, Johnnie Walker, 3M, Airbnb, Clinique, Lemsip, Puma and Grand Marnier to name a few

Employment History

FREELANCE/SELF-EMPLOYED London, UK

(Jan 2018 - Present)

Sound Recordist / Engineer

FOCAL RHYTHM SOUND PRODUCTIONS London, UK

(Jul 2013 - Dec 2017)

Sound Recordist / Engineer

• In charge of all location sound projects, from liaising with clients to budgeting, planning and execution. Also involved in VO and audio post work

SHOWMAKERS PTE LTD Singapore

(2006 - 2007, Apr - Aug 2011)

Assistant Live Sound Engineer / Rigger

• Audio, lighting and image supplier company for live stage events and productions

Academic Qualifications

2011 - 2013: BA (Hons), 1st Class Degree in Audio Production

School of Audio Engineering (SAE), London

2004 - 2007: Diploma in Film, Sound & Video (FSV)

Ngee Ann Polytechnic, Singapore

Related Experiences/Skills

- Previously engaged in 3 band commitments spanning 11 years, garnering a wealth of experience in performance, songwriting, rehearsals and music production.
- \bullet Organiser of Local motion , a fortnightly/monthly music night for original acts at the late Home Club (Singapore).

Others

• Fluent in Mandarin Chinese (speaking, reading and writing)

Selected Portfolio Links

* mainly as a sound recordist unless otherwise stated

Feature / TV Drama

• THE BIKE THIEF (in post)

• TOM AND HIS ZOMBIE WIFE (in post)

• QUEENS OF MYSTERY (2019)

● <u>SHAMED</u> (2017)

• TO TOKYO (2018)

• ANTI-SOCIAL (2015)

Ellipsis Pictures. Directed by Matt Chambers (Boom Operator)

K4K Films. Directed by and starring Kevin Short Sly Fox Productions. Directed by lan Emes

(Episode 1 Sound Trainee)

Minnow Films. Directed by Anthony Philipson Mannequin Films. Directed by Caspar Seale-Jones

(Sound Recordist dailies, Foley Artist, Monster Voice and Foley)

RST Pictures. Directed by Reg Traviss (London Unit)

Commercial / Branded

• BEER HEROES

AIRBNB

FLIPKART

REBTEL3M

PATRIZIA PEPE

The Incredible Kayak Amphibian , The Amazing Crowd Surfer

Hidden Jazz Club piece

Big Billon Days with Virat Kohli

Basketmouth ruins Hollywood Premiere

3M Peltor X Series
Patrizia meets Dua Lipa

Factual / TV & Web Series

PULPED

• WEMBLEY CUP & EE

• ROYAL CARIBBEAN

ME FILM LTD

AGON CHANNEL

Twisted Guide To Life

'Extra Time' with Ander Herrara and Jordan Henderson (2017)

Royal Crush Season 4 (2016) - Production Sound Mixer

Frankie and Emma (2017) Leyton Orient (2014-2015)

Music Video / BTS / Event Coverage

• STURGE MEDIA

GIGGS

• RKIVE PRODUCTIONS

Alter Bridge: Live At The Royal Albert Hall 2017 - London Rehearsal BTS

<u>'(Is It Gangsta) Yes Yes Yes' MV</u> (2013) Africa Centre Summer Festival 2017

Short Film

• FOOD FOR THOUGHT (2016)

• <u>HUSK</u> (2017)

• EQUAL (2017)

Directed by Davide Gentile, in conjunction with World Health Day 2016
Directed by Emily-Seale Jones, music composed by Trevor Jones

(Sound Recordist, Dialogue Editor, Sound Designer & Mixer)

Featuring Last Night in Paris. Directed by Jordan Wi-Fi and Philip Ramhofer

Documentary

• <u>IT TAKES GUTS</u> (in post)

• <u>SKATE LIBERTE</u> (2018)

• <u>ILL</u>, <u>ACTUALLY</u> (2019)

Shot from 2015 to 2019. Produced and directed by Adrienne Grierson Directed by Naomi Berrio-Allen (Sound Recordist, Dialogue Editor, Sound Mixer)

BBC FOUR Born Digital: First Cuts. Directed by Zoe Hunter Gordon

Corporate

BIRD & BIRD

ARABESQUE

LIVING PLANIT

'About Us' video (London Unit)

Temperature Score

Corporate Introduction 2017